A Guide to the Alfred Ezra Mirsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA131
Rockefeller Archive Center
Alfred Ezra Mirsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1927-1974
Rockefeller Archive Center
Mirsky, Alfred E.
FA131
39.6 Cubic Feet
70 boxes; 7 volumes; 4 packages; 6 slide boxes, 36 linear feet
Biographical/Historical note
Alfred Ezra Mirsky, 1900-1974, biochemist and physiologist at The Rockefeller University (earlier RIMR) from 1927 until his death in 1974. Engaged in research on proteins and properties of the cell nucleus. He was one of the first scientists to isolate and characterize the Messenger RNA as the genetic material of the mammalian cells. Founded the Christmas Lectures for high school students held on campus since 1959. As Chairman of the Faculty Committee on Educational Policies, he helped shape policies in restructuring the old Rockeªfeller Institute to a graduate university. He was active in furthering the publication of scientific literature through book publishing and as consultªant to Scientific American. Coeditor with Jean Brachet of The Cell, Volumes I thru VI. Editor of the Journal of General Physiology, 1951-1961.
Biographical Note
1900 Born October 17, Flushing, New York
1918 Graduated Ethical Culture School, New York
1922 A.B. Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
1922-1923 Attended College of Physicians and Surgeons, Columbia University, New York
1924-1926 National Research Council Medical Fellowship
1924-1925 University of Cambridge, Cambridge, England (under Barcroft, J.)
1925-1926 Harvard Medical School, Cambridge, Mass. (under Henderson, L.J.)
1926 Ph.D. University of Cambridge, Cambridge, England
1927 Assistant, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, New York
1930 Associate, RIMR
1935-1936 Visiting Professor, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, California; worked with Linus Pauling and visited China
1940 Associate Member, RIMR
1948 Member, RIMR (1954 title changed to Professor)
1954 Honorary M. D., University of Gothenburg, Sweden
1959 Honorary Professor, University of Santiago, Chile
1964 Laureate in Biological Sciences, University of Palermo, Italy
1965-1972 Librarian, Rockefeller University
1971 Professor Emeritus, Rockefeller University
1974 Died June 19, New York City, Rockefeller University Committee
1954 Committee on Laboratory Helpers and Technicians, RIMR
1957 Chairman, Faculty Committee on Educational Policies, RI
1959 Founded Christmas Lectures for High School Students
1961 Chairman, Committee on Physiology, RI
1967 Faculty Committee, Faculty appointments and promotions, RU
1967 Committee on Biological Sciences, RU
Served
1951-1961 Editor, Journal of General Physiology
Through 1966 on Editorial Board, Journal of General Physiology
1959-1964 Editor with Jean Brachet of The Cell Volumes I thru VI
1965 Advisory Board of Evolutionary Biology
1967 Honorary Editor, Journal of General Physiology
1967-1968 Science Advisor, Institute on Man and Science, Rennselaerville, N.Y.
Member of: American Anthropological Association, American Philosophical Society, National Academy of Sciences, American Chemical Society, Society of Biological Chemists, Society of General Physiologists, Genetics Society of America, American Naturalists Society, Deutsche Akademie der Naturforscher, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Phi Beta Kappa, Society for Cell Biology, Society for the Study of Development and Growth, Harvey Society, Sigma Xi
Family Note
1926 May 25 Married Reba Paeff (d. Nov. 22, 1966)
1927 Dec. 8 Born daughter, Reba (Mrs. Robert Goodman)
1932 Nov. 14 Born son, Jonathan Mirsky
1967 Aug. 24 Married Sonia Wohl
Grandchildren: Reba (Robin) Goodman; Melinda Goodman; Peter Goodman; Nancy Goodman
Arrangement note
Arranged by subject and in chronological order.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Date received: September 1974.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 M679
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: biographical material, correspondence, subject files, manuscripts, lab notes, photographs, slides, laboratory memorabilia, and published papers.
Biology -- Research; Biochemistry; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Biographical materials, 1
  Scope and Contents note
  1965 and 1973 biography prepared for RU Press Bibliography. Record of disposition of books and periodicals from laboratory.
  - Correspondence (Personal) (Box 1)
    Arrangement note
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - Sophomore year John Harvard Scholarship certificate, 1919-1920
    - Birth certificate transcript, 1920 April 6
    - Senior year scholarship certificate Harvard College, 1921-1922
    - Harvard College record, 1922 April 26
    - University of Cambridge, Degree of Doctor of Philosophy, 1927 January 21
    - A.E. Mirsky to Thomas Addis. Holograph, 1931 August 18
    - A.E. Mirsky to [tom Addis?] Holograph. Incomplete, 1934 May 25
    - B.W. Carney to A.E. Mirsky, 1943 June 10
    - Y. Kuniyoshi to A.E. Mirsky, 1944 January 10
    - Letter dealing with dissolution of American-Soviet Science Society, 1948 (?); Typescript carbon
    - W.J.V. Osterhout to A.E. Mirsky congratulations on becoming Member. Holograph, 1948 July 1
    - H.F. Swift to A.E. Mirsky congratulations on becoming Member, 1948 August 12
    - E. Anderson to A.E. Mirsky congratulations on protein lecture, 1950 September 19
    - S. Ochoa to A.E. Mirsky invitation to Linus Pauling dinner, 1954 April 5
    - A.E. Mirsky to S. Ochoa accepting Linus Pauling dinner invitation, 1954 April 7
    - A. Wetmore (Home Secretary, National Academy of Sciences) to A.E. Mirsky elected member National Academy of Sciences, 1954 April 27
    - Group of congratulatory telegrams and letters on election to National Academy of Sciences in chronological order, 1954
    - A.E. Mirsky to A. Wetmore accepting membership in National Academy of Sciences, 1954 April 29
    - Cavalcade of Authors as presented by Chelsea WM and YWHA listing Reba Paeff Mirsky awards, 1954 April 29
    - A. Wetmore to A.E. Mirsky, 1954 May 17
    - A. Wetmore to A.E. Mirsky, 1954 June 7
    - M. Odin to A.E. Mirsky on receipt of honorary M.D. from University of Gothenburg, Sweden, 1954 (circa June 23)
    - A.E. Mirsky to M. Odin, 1954 June 23
    - Sigma Xi membership certificate, 1958 November 25
    - Honorary Member of Faculty of Medicine, University of Santiago, Chile certificate, 1959 December 4
      (See 3b Pkg.).
    - Honorary Member of Biology Society, Santiago, Chile certificate, 1960 January 2
    - E. Cruz-Coke (Chilean Ambassador) to A.E. Mirsky invitation. Holograph, 1960 June 18
    - Unsigned letter to A.E. Mirsky about laboratory work, 1962 August 20
    - A.G. Beam to A.E. Mirsky on Harvey Society life membership, 1963 March 18
    - exchange of letters between A.E. Mirsky and Harvard library on return of book after 37 years, 1963 July thru November
    - M. Gerbasi to A.E. Mirsky on Honorary Biology degree, University of Palermo, 1964 March 31
    - American Philosophical Society membership certificate, 1964 April 24
    - T. Francis to A.E. Mirsky congratulations on American Philosophical Society election, 1964 July 9
    - T.S. Sadaswan to R.P. Mirsky on money gift thank you, 1965 March 3
    - A.E. Mirsky to J. Ross on J. Mirsky thesis typing, 1965 March 31
    - D. Morse to A.E. Mirsky on Librarian appointment. Holograph, 1965 July 6
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences election certificate, 1966 May 11
    - J. Mirsky to Seshachar on Chinese studies in India. Draft, circa 1967?
    - E.K. Meeks to A.E. Mirsky on Reba P. Mirsky memorial folder and book, 1967 March 22
    - E.M. Sithole to A.E. Mirsky on Reba Mirsky death and family reunion, 1967 April 9
    - A.E. Mirsky to E.M. Sithole, 1967 April 11
    - A.E. Mirsky to E.K. Meeks on R.P. Mirsky, 1967 May 18
    - C. McWilliams to A.E. Mirsky enclosing eulogy of A.E. Mirsky oldest sister, 1967 June 23
    - E.K. Meeks to A.E. Mirsky on R.P. Mirsky, 1967 August 4
    - A.E. Mirsky to E.K. Meeks on costs of R.P. Mirsky memorial folder and royalty check, 1968 January 31
    - A.E. Mirsky to K. Wood on R.P. Mirsky, 1968 March 25
    - A.E. Mirsky to Northeastern Illinois State College on E. Sithole employment recommendation, 1968 August 14
    - A.E. Mirsky to E. Meeks on R.P. Mirsky book, 1969 March 3
    - C. Polka to A.E. Mirsky. Holograph. Student question "Is One Race Genetically Better Than Another?", 1971 January (?)
    - A.E. Mirsky to C. Polka. Reply, 1971 February 2
    - G.H. Goldstein to A.E. Mirsky on sending Reba Mirsky photograph, 1971 March 19
    - T.E. Jewell to A.E. Mirsky on 50th anniversary report of 1922 Harvard class, 1971 October 1
    - A.E. Mirsky report for 50th anniversary of 1922 Harvard class, 1972 January (?)
    - R. Colp Jr. (nephew) to Sonya Mirsky on enclosing 1920 August A.E. Mirsky letter to Miriam (sister). Holograph. On sister's first wedding anniversary, 1974 July 9
  - Newspaper clippings (photocopied); Rockefeller Institute Press releases; interviews, 1962 (Box 1)
    "An interview with Dr. Alfred E. Mirsky" Journal of Biology 1962 published by Bronx High School of Science.
  - Obituary material (Box 1)
    Newspapers; RU Press release; RU announcement.
    - Journal of General Physiology v. 64 (1974) pp. 131-133
    - Annals of Internal Medicine v. 81 (1974) p. 313; p. 340
    - Nature v. 251 (1974) p. 363
    - News and Notes v. 5 (July 1974) p. 6
    - Acta Embryologiae Experimentalis 1975 pp. 4-7
    - NABT National Convention 1974, p. 26; p. 51
    - Encyclopedia Britannica Yearbook 1974 "Obituaries", p. 532
    - Note on interment with location map and appropriate correspondence S.W. Mirsky / F. Seitz
    - APS Biographical memoir Yearbook, 1976; p. 100-103
    - King's college, Cambridge, Annual Report, 1979 October
  - Personal collections (Box 1)
    - Correspondence dealing with interest in and purchase of Greek coins, ancient lamps, figures, etc., 1952-1968 (Box 1)
  - Special correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
    Allfrey; Davidson; Crippa.
  - African trip, Summer 1953 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, handwritten memos
    - "Science in Uganda and Union of South Africa"
    - Undated holograph report
      Includes evaluation of J. B. Hutchinson work.
    - Grant application to Ford Foundation forwarded by Sir Andrew Cohen, Governor of Uganda Protectorate, 1954 April 9
      (For A. E. Mirsky evaluation see Box 7 Ford Foundation).
  - Rolladex file; membership cards (Box 1)
  - Phillips Brooks appointment calendars, 1966-1974 (Box 2)
  - Photographs (Box 3)
    - Alfred E. Mirsky photographs (some duplicates), 1926-1973
    - Assorted photographs: associates, famous scientists, scientist friends; many bearing signatures
  - American Philosophical Society membership certificate (Package 3a)
  - Honorary Member of Faculty of Medicine, University of Santiago, Chile certificate (Package 3b)
  - Honorary Member of Biology Society, Santiago, Chile certificate (Package 3b)
  - Picture story of Laboratory (workers and techniques) as photographed for Life Science Library. Collection of slides (used and unused). Each slide is identified where possible (Box 4)
  - Pfeiffer, John. The Cell 1 bound volume, Life Science Library (Box 4a)
- Correspondence, 1929 1942-1974; 2
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - A-All (Box 5)
    - Abelson, Philip. Science, 2 letters
    - Abemayor, Michael, 1 letter
    - Abemayor, Violet, 2 letters
    - Academic Press, 50 letters
      Correspondents.
    - Acs, George, 1 letter
    - Acton, Emily, 2 letters
    - Adams, Mark. Concerning Marshak paper, 2 letters
    - Adams, William S. Request for P.A.T. Levene samples, 2 letters
    - Adrouny, George A. Tulane address, 1965 March 8; 5 letters
    - Advances in Genetics, 1 letter
    - Advocate, Seymour, 1 letter
    - Ahmad, M.S., 1 letter
    - Albritton, Errett, 1 letter
    - Aleksandrowicz, W., 2 letters
    - Alessandri, H., 3 letters
    - Alferov, V.V. Visiting Russian scientist, 1965 October-1966 January; 13 letters
    - Allen, LeRoy. Concerning N.C. Panda, 3 letters
    - Allfrey, Vincent G. Primarily material about Allfrey, 24 letters
  - Alo-Apt (Box 5)
    - Aloe Scientific Co., 6 letters
    - Alston, Ralph, 3 letters
    - Altschuller, Gregory I., 2 letters
    - Ambellan, Elisabeth. Admission application, 2 letters
    - American Anthropological Association, 2 letters
    - American Anthropologist, 1 letter
    - American Chemical Society, 20 letters
      Includes review of papers by: Kay, Simmons and Dounce; Dounce and O'Connell.
    - American Heart Journal. Review of "Human Biochemical Genetics", 4 letters
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences (AIBS), 3 letters
    - American Lectures in Living Chemistry, 2 letters
    - American Naturalist, 31 letters
      Includes correspondence with L.C. Dunn on publication materials.
    - American Society of Biological Chemists, 16 letters
      Includes referee opinions.
    - American Society for Cell Biology, 1 letter
    - American Society of Zoologists, 2 letters
    - Anderson, Paul N., 2 letters
    - Anderson, Richmond. Rockefeller Foundation grant for Yamada and Osawa, 2 letters
    - Anfinsen, Christian B., 5 letters
    - Annamalai University. To examine Shri K. Madhavan thesis, 3 letters
    - Anson, Mortimor L. Holographs, 4 letters
    - Apte, B. K., 2 letters
  - Ar-Az (Box 5)
    - Archibald, R.M., 1 letter
    - Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics. Evaluation of manuscripts, 38 letters
    - Arnold, Helen. Student progress examination, 4 letters
    - Aronoff, Sam, 2 letters
    - Asch, George, 2 letters
    - Atchley, Wm. A., 3 letters
    - Atomic Energy Commission (U.S.). Review of G.L. Patel and V.J. Wulff research proposals, 4 letters
    - Australian Research Grants Committee. Review of C.M. Mauritzen grant application, 2 letters
    - Axelrod, A.E. Evaluation of MacDonald Cave, 2 letters
    - Azulay, Ann, 2 letters
    - Azmitia, E. Charles. Admission application, 3 letters
  - B-Bellc (Box 5)
    - Babbitt, Adeline E., 1 letter
    - Bachvaroff, Radoslav B., 4 letters
    - Bachvarova, Faulkner Rosemary, 7 letters
    - Backus, Robert C., 2 letters
    - Bagchi, Mihir, 2 letters
    - Bahr, G.F., 2 letters
    - Bailey, K. Job inquiry for D.S. Robinson, 1 letter
    - Baker, Howard H., 1 letter
    - Balinsky, B.I. Barry Fabian application, 1 letter
    - Ball, Alice D. Publications for libraries abroad, 2 letters
    - Ball, Meridian R. Recommendation for John Cibra, 2 letters
    - Ballonoff, Marilyn, 2 letters
    - Banerji, D.M. Admission application, 2 letters
    - Banerji, S.P., 6 letters
    - Barak, Eve I. Admission application, 7 letters
    - Barbieri, F.D. Job inquiry for C.R. Legname, 2 letters
    - Barigozzi, Claudio, 9 letters
      Includes photographs of chromosomes Barnard, R.D. (1).
    - Barnett, S.A. Student seminars, 1964 1968; 35 letters
    - Barnicot, Nigel A., 2 letters
    - Barnum, Cyrus P., 1 letter
    - Barowsky, Sadie, 2 letters
    - Barsacchi, G., 2 letters
    - Barthelmess, A., 2 letters
    - Bashirelahi, Nasser, 1 letter
    - Basic Books. Review of J.A.V. Butler "Inside the Living Cell"; Jean Rostand "Can Man Be Modified", 5 letters
    - Battin, Wm., 2 letters
    - Bayless, Wm., 11 letters
      Includes item on Selected Writings of Herbert Gasser.
    - Bean, Barry. Job inquiry for K. Malathi, 4 letters
    - Beam, Alexander. Items on: 1961 December AAAS talk; J.B.S. Haldane visit to RI, 4 letters
    - Beerman, W. Tübingen, Miescher Centennial Symposium talk, 1969 September 14-18; 10 letters
    - Bellco Glass Inc., 3 letters
  - Belli-Bow (Box 5)
    - Bellin, Judith S. laboratory assistant, 1956-1958; 8 letters
    - Bello, Jake. Research proposal evaluation, 3 letters
    - Benison, Saul, 6 letters
    - Bennett, Dorothea, 2 letters
    - Benson, Ellis S., 1 letter
    - Bergmann, Ernst O., 2 letters
    - Bernstein, R.E., 1 letter
    - Bereiter, Carl, 1 letter
    - Berk, Evelyn, 2 letters
    - Berlowitz, Larry, 2 letters
    - Bermuda Biological Research Laboratory. worked with H. Ris, 1948 summer; 5 letters
    - Bernard, W. Electron micrographs for Scientific American, 6 letters
    - Bersworth Chemical Co., 1 letter
    - Besser, Marianne, 2 letters
    - Beth Israel Medical Center. Addresses, 1966 June 1972 February; 3 letters
    - Bett, Bryan, 2 letters
    - Bhargava, P.M., 1964 January; 31 letters
      Includes 1964 January Hyderabad, India Symposium on Nucleic Acids; visit to RU.
    - Bhowmick, D.K., 2 letters
    - Bing, R.J., 1 letter
    - Biochemistry. Review of Sherod, Johnson and Chalkley paper, 4 letters
    - Biochimica et Biophysica Acta. Review of papers by: M. Kamiyama and T.Y. Wang; T.L. Shirley and R.C.C. Huang; A.W. Johnson, J.A. Wilhelm, D.N. Wad, L.S. Hnilica; D. Gallwitz and I. Sures, 15 letters
    - Birge, W.J., 1 letter
    - Biswas, B.B. Thesis opinion, 8 letters
    - Bittar, E.E., 4 letters
    - Black, M., 1 letter
    - Blackburn, S., 1 letter
    - Blinks, L.R., 6 letters
    - Bloomberg, Ben, 1 letter
    - Bobbs-Merrill Co., 1 letter
    - Boettger, R., 25 letters
    - Boivin, André, 1 letter
    - Bolis, L., 2 letters
    - Bolton, J.L. 1 holograph, 3 letters
    - Bone, D.H., 2 letters
    - Bonner, James, 1963 April 30-May 2; 5 letters
      Includes Cal Tech conference.
    - Bonneville, Mary, 1 letter
    - Bookbinding. Laboratory collection, 21 letters
    - Borun, Thaddeus W., 1 letter
    - Bourdillon, Jaques, 1 letter
    - Boutry, G.A., 1 letter
    - Bowers, John Z., 2 letters
  - Boy-Bri (Box 5)
    - Boyce Thompson Institute. seminar, 1955 March 16; 4 letters
    - Brachet, Jean, 67 letters
      Primarily correspondence on The Cell; includes correspondence on meetings: 1955 August Brussels; 1958 June 8-15 Brussels; 1965 Milan.
    - Bradley, D.M., 2 letters
    - Braggio, John Thomas
    - Brain Information Service, 4 letters
    - Bram, Stanley, 2 letters
    - Braun, Armin C., 7 letters
    - Braun, Werner, 1 letter
    - Braunstein, A.E., 2 letters
    - Brawerman, George, 1 letter
    - Brayshaw, De Brunner N., 3 letters
    - Bresler, S.E., 5 letters
    - Brickman, W.W., 2 letters
    - Bright, Mabel, 3 letters
    - Brink, Frank, 1958-1971; 17 letters
  - Br (Box 5)
    - Bronk, Detlev W., 1954-1972; 120 letters (Box 5)
      Includes appointments to various RU committees Comments on George Nemethy. Report from Biology Committee with comments M. Kanungo manuscript review.
    - Bronn-Buz (Box 6)
    - Bronner, Felix, 1 letter (Box 6)
    - Brooks, Chandler McC. State University NY (Downstate Medical Center) symposium, 1965 November 26-27; 6 letters (Box 6)
    - Brooks, Margaret, 1 letter (Box 6)
    - Brown, Roy E., 2 letters (Box 6)
    - Brown, Wm. O., 3 letters (Box 6)
    - Bryson, Vernon, 2 letters (Box 6)
    - Bubenik, G., 3 letters (Box 6)
    - Buck, John. Woods Hole, Society of General Physiologist symposium, 1951 June 20-22; 4 letters (Box 6)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 2 letters (Box 6)
    - Burch, George. Tulane addresses; 3 items on history of sickle cell anemia, 1954 1965 March; 26 letters (Box 6)
    - Burdette, Walter J. Job inquiry for Ute Gröschel, 4 letters (Box 6)
    - Burdick, Carolyn J., 34 letters (Box 6)
      Includes recommendations for Burgos, Mario (1).
    - Burlingham, Susan. Admission application with college transcript, 5 letters (Box 6)
    - Busch, H., 8 letters (Box 6)
    - Butler, J.A.V., 7 letters (Box 6)
    - Buzzati-Traverso, A.A. Alberto Monroy recommendation, 2 letters (Box 6)
  - C-Chas (Box 6)
    - Cabello, Julio. Santiago, University of Chile addresses Callan, H.G. (9), 1960; 2 letters
    - Cambridge Symposium. Cambridge,."The Cell Nucleus" with outline, 1959; 1 letter
    - Cambridge University Press, 2 letters
    - Campagne, R.N., 6 letters
    - Campbell, Charles. DNA article Mirsky and Ris, 9 letters
    - Campbell, P.N., 1 letter
    - Campo. Anthony, 8 letters
    - Campo, Robert. Student progress evaluation, 1 letter
    - Canalco Inc., 3 letters
    - Cancer Research, 6 letters
      Includes reviews of 2 papers Cannon, Patricia (1).
    - Cantor, A.J. Research proposal evaluation, 2 letters
    - Carnahan, Kenneth R., 2 letters
    - Caro, Frank, 1 letter
    - Carruthers, C., 2 letters
    - Caspari, E.W., 5 letters
    - Castillo, R., 2 letters
    - Catcheside, D.G. Hiroto Naora recommendation, 5 letters
    - Cattell, McKeen, 1 letter
    - Cecil, R.P., 2 letters
    - Cell Differentiation, 1 letter
    - Center for Advanced Study in The Behavioral Sciences, 3 letters
    - Ceriotti, G., 1 letter
    - Chakraborty, A.K., 2 letters
    - Chance, B., 2 letters
    - Chanda, S.K., 1 holograph, 4 letters
    - Chandrasekar, S., 2 letters
    - Chang, K.C., 2 letters
    - Chantrenne, H., 2 letters
    - Chapelle, A., 3 letters
    - Chase, Allan, 14 letters
  - Chass-Cra (Box 6)
    - Chassot-Poncet, P., 1 letter
    - Cherniss, H. Concerning Ludwig Edelstein, 6 letters
    - Chiarelli, B., 2 letters
    - Childs, Barton, 1 letter
    - Chin, J.M., 2 letters
    - Ciba Foundation, 1 letter
    - Cirker, Hayward, 1 letter
    - City College. address, 1964 October 8; 3 letters
    - Clain-Stefanelli, V. Numismatics, 5 letters
    - Clark, Grahame, 1 letter
    - Clausen, D.F., 2 letters
    - Cleary, J.T., 1 letter
    - Clever, U., 2 letters
    - Clinchy, E. Institute on Man and Science, July 10 Union College addresses, 1967 July 10 1967 July 12; 8 letters
    - Cocioba, I.D., 1 letter
    - Cohen, E.G.D., 2 letters
      Related Materials
      Cohen, Jack S. See under Avery, Oswald Theodore in Box 29.
    - Cohen, Jules, 1 letter
    - Cohen, Jack S.
      [See under: Avery, Oswald Theodore in Box no. 29].
    - Cohen, Sasson, 2 letters
    - Cohen, Seymour, 1957-1963; 45 letters
    - Cohn, Elizabeth. Item on 1959 high school students summer biology course at RI, 2 letters
    - Cole, Leonard J., 3 letters
    - Cole, Paula, 2 letters
    - Cole, R. David, 1 letter
    - Coleman, Wm., 1 letter
    - Collier, Jack R. Collins, V.K. (2), 2 letters
    - Colp, Ralph. Recommendations for Comings, David (1), 4 letters
    - Committee for Survival, 5 letters
    - Congress of Bellagio, 1 letter
    - Conklin, Harold C. Yale address, 1966 December 8; 4 letters
    - Connelly, Clarence. Review of papers, 2 letters
    - Coogan, Pat, 1 letter
    - Cook, S.F., 2 letters
    - Coombs, Susan, 2 letters
    - Corbiere, H., 1 letter
    - Corden, R.E., 1 letter
    - Cori, Osvaldo, 1 letter
    - Corner, George W. paper at APS, 1967 April; 8 letters
    - Corning Glass Works, 1 letter
    - Cotsonas, G.E., 3 letters
    - Cousins, L.L., 1 letter
    - Cowden, R.R., 2 letters
    - Craddock, Valda M., 8 letters
    - Craig, Emmy, 1 letter
    - Craig, Lyman, 1 letter
    - Crampton, Charles, 1 letter
    - Cranefield, Paul F., 4 letters
  - Cre-Cus (Box 6)
    - Cresswell, H.A. Films for RIMR, 4 letters
    - Crippa, Marco, 53 letters
    - Crump, E. Perry, 1 letter
    - Cullen, Mary Rose, 2 letters
    - Cunningham, F., 1 letter
    - Curtis, Helen, 2 letters
    - Curtis, Howard, 1 letter
    - Cushing, John. Bruce Merrifield recommendation, 2 letters
  - Davidson, Eric H., 1958-1968; 90 letters (Box 6)
  - D-Des (Box 6)
    - Daedalus, 1 letter
    - Dahl, Lewis K., 2 letters
    - Dales, Sam. Betty Pogo recommendation, 1 letter